<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<!-- This is a WordPress eXtended RSS file generated by WordPress as an export of your site. -->
<!-- It contains information about your site's posts, pages, comments, categories, and other content. -->
<!-- You may use this file to transfer that content from one site to another. -->
<!-- This file is not intended to serve as a complete backup of your site. -->

<!-- To import this information into a WordPress site follow these steps: -->
<!-- 1. Log in to that site as an administrator. -->
<!-- 2. Go to Tools: Import in the WordPress admin panel. -->
<!-- 3. Install the "WordPress" importer from the list. -->
<!-- 4. Activate & Run Importer. -->
<!-- 5. Upload this file using the form provided on that page. -->
<!-- 6. You will first be asked to map the authors in this export file to users -->
<!--    on the site. For each author, you may choose to map to an -->
<!--    existing user on the site or to create a new user. -->
<!-- 7. WordPress will then import each of the posts, pages, comments, categories, etc. -->
<!--    contained in this file into your site. -->

<!-- generator="WordPress/4.0.23" created="2018-05-28 21:17" -->
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:excerpt="http://wordpress.org/export/1.2/excerpt/"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:wp="http://wordpress.org/export/1.2/"
>

<channel>
	<title>Amanda Brookfield</title>
	<link>http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog</link>
	<description>Blog of the best-selling Penguin author</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 28 May 2018 21:17:56 +0000</pubDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<wp:wxr_version>1.2</wp:wxr_version>
	<wp:base_site_url>http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog</wp:base_site_url>
	<wp:base_blog_url>http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog</wp:base_blog_url>

	<wp:author><wp:author_id>3</wp:author_id><wp:author_login>Amanda</wp:author_login><wp:author_email>amandabrookfield@gmail.com</wp:author_email><wp:author_display_name><![CDATA[Amanda]]></wp:author_display_name><wp:author_first_name><![CDATA[Amanda]]></wp:author_first_name><wp:author_last_name><![CDATA[Brookfield]]></wp:author_last_name></wp:author>


	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.0.23</generator>

	<item>
				<title>Summer Newsletter 2012</title>
		<link>http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=7</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2012 18:00:35 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Amanda]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=7</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[At the moment I am something of an expert on Roman Britain. It is a bulge of unlikely knowledge, acquired thanks to a week spent walking Hadrian's Wall (the middle stretch of 40 miles or so, between Newcastle and Carlisle). Six days following the impressive, snaking stone remains of wall, forts, towers and milestones made it impossible not to want to bury one's nose in a guide book to soak up everything one could. It probably helped that the weather was mostly fabulous – miles and miles of Scotland and England laid out like a feast – and that I had taken the precaution of investing in some sturdy comfortable boots. But what impressed me most consistently was the knowledge that I was clambering along something that had been put in place TWO THOUSAND YEARS AGO.
<!--more-->

Here are some interesting facts before I forget them:
<ol>
	<li>Hadrian built the wall to keep out the 'Barbarians'…who turned into the Scottish nation we know and love today!</li>
	<li>Hadrian was gay and loved a beautiful young man with whom he was unable to share his life on account of a harridan wife who happened to be the daughter of someone very very important whom he did not want to piss off. (See? Already some of the more solid aspects of my new erudition – like names - are slipping away.)</li>
	<li>Hadrian spent years simply travelling round the boundaries of his massive global Roman Empire trying to keep it strong. No wonder his marriage to the harridan felt the strain.</li>
	<li>The Romans occupied Britain for almost THREE HUNDRED AND FIFTY years. ie the equivalent to us, now, of having been ruled by strangers since the end of the Seventeenth Century. That is a long time.</li>
	<li>Then they just left!! (To focus strength on other, more important boundary issues). Which must have been exciting for the occupied locals – 'freedom! At last! But also traumatic, because three centuries in, lots of Romans and Brits had fallen in love with each other and made babies and families and so on. Not to mention the other problem that they took all their famous expertise (underground heating, road-building etc ) with them. It is no coincidence that we nose-dived into the Dark Ages as a result, a dodgy patch that lasted for some five hundred years.</li>
</ol>
There. Done. A written outline of stuff that I soon might not remember, and already sadly lacking some of the names, dates and figures that were at my fingertips this time last week. No, it's not dementia – not just yet anyway (she touches wood); but simply one of the irksome aspects of having edged into one's sixth decade. My brain still remembers crates of things, it's just the question of what makes it into those crates that is no longer certain. Yes, that is what annoys me the most – the lack of control – rather than the memory slippage itself.

I console myself that we are in a more 'immediate' age now anyway. Facts are a finger-touch away on our keyboards, freeing our intellectual and creative energies for the instant expression and interaction offered by communications' technology. Adaptable creature that I am, (cue hollow laughter from close family and friends), I am actually starting to get the hang of it and, dare I say, to enjoy it! I tweet. (@ABrookfield1). My website is getting a make-over. A Facebook page (facebook.com/amandabrookfield) is imminent. All three will link up. And soon this hitherto quarterly newsletter will transmogrify into a more regular blog. It might be different, better, shorter, longer…I have no idea. I intend to make the most of this new 'freedom' and let my thoughts flow where they will. The only thing I know for sure is that I am looking forward to it.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>7</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2012-07-01 18:00:35</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2012-07-01 18:00:35</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>closed</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>closed</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>summer-newsletter-2012</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="facebook"><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="newsletters"><![CDATA[Newsletters]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="romans"><![CDATA[Romans]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_old_slug</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[summer-newsletter]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_jd_twitter</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_jd_tweet_this</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_jd_clig</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_jd_bitly</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_jd_wp</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_jd_yourls</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_jd_url</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_jd_target</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_jd_wp_twitter</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_jd_post_meta_fixed</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[true]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_jd_post_meta_fixed</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[true]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_jd_post_meta_fixed</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[true]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_jd_post_meta_fixed</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[true]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
				<title>Spring Newsletter 2012</title>
		<link>http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=32</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 20:40:02 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Amanda]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=32</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[It is March and I am sunburnt. This is not from a skiing holiday or a Caribbean jaunt, but because I sat outside having a sandwich lunch in Soho Square yesterday with a writing friend. We talked intensely and enjoyably for over three hours, mostly about writing. He writes film scripts not books, thus facing the same dilemmas but having to solve them in different ways. We were in the shade of a tree but this Spring heat-wave is proving powerful. My nose is a colour not too dissimilar from the camellia bud outside my front door.<!--more-->

I don't have many writing friends. Over the years I have come to realise that this is a deliberate, albeit subconscious (and oxymoronic) personal 'policy' of mine, rather than because of any lack of popularity among fellow my artists. By nature I am a very sociable animal. Lunches, drinks, parties – conversation of all kinds remains life-blood to me, both as a writer and as a human. And when it comes to meeting specifically literary social demands, I always enjoy myself - attending events and mixing with other authors (I even tweet! <a href="http://twitter.com/#!/ABrookfield1" target="_blank">@ABrookfield1</a> for those interested). But in the general stream of my everyday working life, there is absolutely no doubt that I feel a strong need to inhabit the most private space I can. Not for me the showing and sharing of work-in-progress. Nor do I want to hear other novelists talk (as I do!) about their storylines, characters, deadlines, deals. It is not lack of curiosity. It is not envy. Instead, it is more like a deep wariness of the potentially debilitating recognition that my small 'voice' is just one among millions, part of a clamour, shouting (not loud enough) to be heard. In order to feel 'loud enough' - unique enough - what I, personally, need to maintain, is the heady and perhaps delusional conviction, that if I do not write what I write, no one else will. That only I can my tell my stories in the way that I do; that without me they would not get written.

If this smacks of insecurity then that would be correct. I think most artists are insecure. All art is derivative – of life, of other art. To forge new shapes within that vast constraint takes courage and self-belief. Creating the right space for that courage and self-belief to flourish is half the battle.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>32</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2012-04-01 20:40:02</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2012-04-01 20:40:02</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>closed</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>spring-newsletter-2012</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="newsletters"><![CDATA[Newsletters]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_jd_tweet_this</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_jd_twitter</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_jd_clig</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_jd_bitly</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_jd_wp</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_jd_yourls</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_jd_url</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_jd_target</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_jd_wp_twitter</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_jd_post_meta_fixed</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[true]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_jd_post_meta_fixed</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[true]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
				<title>Autumn Newsletter 2011</title>
		<link>http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=36</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2011 20:43:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Amanda]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=36</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[For me there are very distinct cycles in the production of a novel: the thinking bit, the scribbling a few notes bit, the grab-it-by-the-throat-and-start bit, the press-on-even-though-it-feels-impossible bit, then the final strait, when you know the end is in sight but try not to look at it too hard for fear of rushing, or losing your nerve or indeed doing anything to undermine all the hard graft that has got you thus far.  I am in that final strait now.  I am working so many hours at my desk that my sons are starting to give me funny looks.  They have also, unbidden, begun to do uncharacteristically useful things like clear up after themselves and empty the dishwasher.  Yesterday my eldest told me that he had cleaned the mirror in the upstairs bathroom.  I hugged him hard, even though there are about a thousand things I would have chosen ahead of such a domestic detail.  Like buying food, or cleaning the loo, or taking the boxes of stuff for recycling.  I am not on top of things, you see, and it’s starting to show.<!--more-->

It is when I get to this stage of the proceedings that I realise I am an obsessive.  For the truth is in my current frame of mind I do not want to do ANYTHING but write.  Until my book is as good as it can be.  That is ALL I want to do.  Everything else – social discourse, shopping, cooking, conversation, sleep – feelings like an irksome interruption to the fulfilment of that goal; even going to Northern Spain for a week at the end of August, a trip organised by my husband, felt like a wrench.  ‘Go on your own,’ I wanted to say.  ‘Leave me alone.  I need to finish this thing so that I can stop thinking about it.’  The holiday was good, but I could barely conceal my relief to get home.  I am now back into seven hour stints at my desk.  Friends and near-strangers alike, daring to ask how I am, are likely to be subjected to a detailed outpouring about that day’s travails with my work, instead of receiving the brief response of ‘fine’ that they had expected. I am not proud of this.  It is embarrassing.  And dull.  And soon I shall have no friends left, let alone family. Next weekend we have a big milestone birthday party to attend in a far-flung place that will involve being away overnight.  It is a fancy dress party and I have elected to go as Miss Scarlet.  I need to go hunting for a blonde wig and a red dress, which I don’t want to do.  Red shoes and a red handbag would be good too, but I don’t want to look for those either.  I don’t want to go to the party.  I want to be left alone.  I want to close my study door and work.

A very bright light in this self-obsessive tunnel has been the new Alan Hollinghurst novel, ‘The Stranger’s Child’.  I cannot believe he has not made it onto the Booker shortlist.  Except yes, I can, because the craft and drift of the book is so beautifully subtle I expect the judges got scared that it would not appeal to a mass audience.  It should appeal to a mass audience.  It is a stunning achievement, each sentence breathtakingly honed and perfectly poised.  I loved every moment.  Embroiled in my own, much more mediocre labours, I do my best to it from my mind…labours, to which of course I must now return.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>36</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2011-10-11 20:43:18</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2011-10-11 20:43:18</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>closed</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>autumn-newsletter-2011</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="newsletters"><![CDATA[Newsletters]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_jd_tweet_this</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[yes]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_jd_twitter</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_jd_clig</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_jd_bitly</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_jd_wp</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_jd_yourls</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_jd_url</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_jd_target</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_jd_wp_twitter</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_jd_post_meta_fixed</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[true]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_jd_post_meta_fixed</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[true]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
				<title>Winter Newsletter 2011</title>
		<link>http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=41</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 20:44:45 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Amanda]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=41</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[Each year I am struck by the way Christmas is 'made' to happen. An act of collective, steely determination by a species determined to find something to help it through the winter. Each year I resist, through gritted teeth, then succumb. I am at the point of starting to succumb now. I have made a batch of mince pies. I have written two thirds of my Christmas cards. I have bought scores of presents, while still feeling, in some vague way, that there are scores more still to purchase. It feels like a mountain to climb, but one that I shall enjoy when I get to the peak, by which I mean that moment when I stare about me in blurred satisfaction at piles of torn wrapping paper and smiling faces an hour or so post the Queen's Speech on Saturday 25th, (the blur coming from a vast lunch that has included a couple of glasses of wine and a spot of port).<!--more-->

Christmas is only ONE DAY after all, as a wise friend counselled me recently, when I was fretting, about Work and Life and how to fit it all in. After it, God willing, there will be January. And February. The 'organising' part of me has made some preparation for these too, in the form of the acquisition of a super-lightweight snow shovel off Amazon (an American one…they know a thing or two over there about clearing their drives…on the East coast anyway) as well as a set of 'snow-gripper' thingamies to attach to my shoes/boots. This is not because I am totally decrepid. Not yet. I am relatively advanced in years, but also relatively fit. No, the problem is that we live in a 'dip' – surrounded on all sides by steep hills. During the last two snowy winters I discovered that this could mean even walking to the local shops was impossible, or at least mildly dangerous – the challenge of getting to the shops only surpassed by the far greater difficulty of slithering safely home again, overladen bags banging against one's knees.

For me the New Year holds the other, daunting prospect of starting to think about my next book. Till then I keep telling myself I am not 'allowed' to think about it, that it doesn't matter, that it can wait in line behind all the other things that must happen between now and 2012. It is only six weeks or so since I finished my most recent manuscript, you see, and so a certain 'rest' period is called for. It proved a bit of beast too, the last one, kicking and screaming till the end, as some of them do; a fact which I'm hoping means it might be my best yet. (I cannot be the only writer who likes to labour - under the illusion at least - of continued self-improvement!). So I feel I owe myself the indulgence of a brief guilt-free window, a patch of time in which I can savour the completion of one job before the pressure cranks up for the next.

It is hard, though. Well-intentioned enquiries from friends about the finishing of one manuscript invariably lead, often in the same breath, to questions about the next, as if the imagination is some kind of handy conveyor belt, pushing out ideas like sausages. If only. Mine, I have learned, requires periods not just of non-pressure but of wily nurturing. There is nothing it likes better than for me to pretend that I will have no need of it again. Ever. Then, like a hard-to-get to lover or a wayward child, it deigns – if I keep my back turned - to start playing ball.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>41</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2011-01-01 20:44:45</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2011-01-01 20:44:45</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>closed</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>winter-newsletter-2011</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="newsletters"><![CDATA[Newsletters]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_jd_tweet_this</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[yes]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_jd_twitter</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_jd_clig</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_jd_bitly</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_jd_wp</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_jd_yourls</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_jd_url</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_jd_target</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_jd_wp_twitter</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_jd_post_meta_fixed</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[true]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_jd_post_meta_fixed</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[true]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
				<title>August 3rd - Olympic Note</title>
		<link>http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=73</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 03 Aug 2012 12:22:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Amanda]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=73</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[I am not an attention-seeker. (Cue scoffs from people who think they know me well. To which I reply, I am someone who loves attention while often being too shy to seek it out, which is quite a different thing). Anyway, the point is, yesterday I went to the Olympics where I found myself wearing a large plastic Union Jack - a gift from the nice British Airways people hanging round the final turning to the velodrome. (There are lots and lots of nice people all around the Olympic site - inside and out. For that alone, a trip there is life-changingly extraordinary). So there I was, draped in my flag and grinning to myself (I was going to watch CHRIS HOY and VICTORIA PENDLETON after all) when I was approached by first one TV crew (from America), then another (from Australia), asking for sound-bites about the day, the cycling, the Olympics. Two more interviews (with BBC radio) followed immediately after the tremendous sprint final for the gold medal, when - it has to be said - my flag-flinging delight had reached new eye-catching heights. That made for a grand total of four invitations to speak into a microphone. Four separate opportunities to stand out and be heard. I wish I could say that I rose to them all with aplomb, blowing away my interviewers (and potential audiences) with pithy, original utterances. I am a 'wordsmith' after all. Words are what I DO. But instead I could summon nothing but platitudes - all the phrases you think you would never be dumb enough to say - albeit delivered with the wildest enthusiasm.

The crushing verdict of my twenty three year old son afterwards was: "Mum, you were like a deranged seven year old".
Apologies then, if anyone saw/heard me. I am thinking of keeping my head down for a while.
But oh my goodness I enjoyed myself.

GO TEAM GB!!!!]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>73</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2012-08-03 12:22:39</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2012-08-03 12:22:39</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>closed</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>august-3rd-olympic-note</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="newsletters"><![CDATA[Newsletters]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_jd_tweet_this</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[yes]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_jd_twitter</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_jd_clig</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_jd_bitly</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_jd_wp</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_jd_yourls</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_jd_url</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_jd_target</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_jd_wp_twitter</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:1:{i:0;s:83:"I've just put a new post on my blog:  August 3rd - Olympic Note http://goo.gl/lxraJ";}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_jd_post_meta_fixed</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[true]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[3]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_jd_post_meta_fixed</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[true]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_jd_goo</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[http://goo.gl/lxraJ]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_jd_post_meta_fixed</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[true]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
				<title>September 13th</title>
		<link>http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=90</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov -0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Amanda]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=90</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[Funny thing a holiday.  With the booking of it there's definitely joy, coupled with relief (Job Done) but also trepidation, in case one's non-refundable deposit has gone into the maws of a place that will prove horrible/wet/a rip-off.  As the date of departure approaches, such fears are replaced by mounting and pleasurable anticipation: <em>I am going to get away from it all! </em><em>To somewhere HOT and EXOTIC!  I am going to READ NOVELS and DRINK and DE-STRESS! </em>Until, that is, the eve of departure arrives, when the list of still-do pre-holiday chores - cancel papers, organise cat-feeding, empty bins, clear out fridge, issue alarm codes to relevant persons, buy at least one new holiday garment, phone the mother, PACK...to name but a few - prompts a silent shriek inside one's head along the lines of : Why Am I Going Away When It Would Be So Much Simpler, So Much NICER To Be Staying At Home?'

The journey is horrible.  The journey is always horrible.  No sleep for fear of missing the flight.  Said flight being delayed after a dawn start.  OVer-spending at the airport.  Plastic food.  The discomfort of the seat.  The screaming child.  The difficulty of finding the right bus, the right road.  Everything taking hours and hours longer than it was supposed to.  One's clothes sticking to one's skin.  Prickly heat.  A strange bed.  The forgotten, vital item eg Aftersun lotion...

And then, quite quickly - usually about 12 hours in my experience - all such horrors are forgotten.  Time slows.  The holiday begins.  Sleeping, eating, drinking, swimming, READING!  (In my case four stunning novels that will enrich the lives of every single person wise enough to treat themselves: 'Don't Let's Go To The Dogs Tonight' by Alexandra Fuller, 'Stoner' by John Williams, 'At Mrs Lippincote's' by Elizabeth Taylor and 'State of Wonder' by Ann Patchett.  With such luxuries, even the presence of the sun starts to matter less, though maybe I say this with the smugness of one whose chosen Greek Island provided just 5 minutes of daytime rain through the course of an entire week.

&nbsp;]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>90</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2012-09-13 12:02:40</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>closed</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>draft</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="newsletters"><![CDATA[Newsletters]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[3]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_jd_tweet_this</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[yes]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
				<title>September Blues</title>
		<link>http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=93</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 14 Sep 2012 17:26:07 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Amanda]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=93</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[Part of me is still on my Greek Island.  It rained for five minutes in seven days.  My skin is full of sun, my brain rested and still refusing to come to heel.  I read four stunning books: 'Don't Let's Go To The Dogs Tonight, by Alexandra Fuller, 'State of Wonder' by Ann Patchett, 'At Mrs Lippincote's' by Elizabeth Taylor and 'Stoner' by John Williams.  I recommend all four unreservedly.  They are all life-enriching stories, each as different from the other as one could imagine.  I read hard copies.  They are scattered around me now on my desk, the corners beaten, the pages fat with pool-splashes and drops of sun lotion; looking as books should look in my view, each a package of memories that extends far beyond the remit of the stories they contain.  I may be a romantic ( I <em>am </em>a romantic!) but I offer that observation as a fact not a sentiment.  Electronic reads are efficient, worthy conduits of the written word, but as a replacement for books there is an added human dimension that they can never deliver.

I am in wistful mood then.  My tanned feet are cold beneath my desk.  (In a state of post-holiday denial about the UK weather, I am still wearing flip-flops.)  But the beaten books remain a comfort.   Glancing at 'Stoner', my thoughts drift back to the high, hot, smooth slab of rock in the Ionian Sea on which I finished reading it.  I was lying on a towel on my back in the evening sun, my beach bag a comfy pillow, the backdrop of sky around the pages a rich flawless blue through my sunglasses.  It has been a tough year.  But by the closing paragraphs a peace had filled me, the like of which I had not thought to know again and which makes the book a friend, a fellow traveller, safely returned.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>93</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2012-09-14 17:26:07</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2012-09-14 17:26:07</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>closed</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>september-blues</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="newsletters"><![CDATA[Newsletters]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[3]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_jd_tweet_this</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[yes]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_jd_target</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[http://amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=93]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_jd_goo</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[http://goo.gl/IiFU6]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_jd_wp_twitter</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:1:{i:0;s:73:"I've just put a new post on my blog:  September Blues http://goo.gl/IiFU6";}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
				<title>October Post</title>
		<link>http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=104</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 28 Oct 2012 17:29:30 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Amanda]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=104</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[I am an 'old-fashioned' author, not anti-technology (I love my Sony Vaio...it has a BIG screen!), but in the sense of being deeply committed both to books as objects for treasuring and to the tactile power of the written word.  To me no thrill can ever replace the beauty of a smooth, plump hand-addressed envelope landing on my door mat: running one's finger under the flap, relishing the knowledge that the words and thoughts committed to the page(s) inside have taken that extra care and effort necessitated by the absence of a delete button.  I like writing letters for the same reason: the pleasure of the pen in my hand, the flow of ink across a clean page, the way one's thoughts focus on the person for whom the words are intended, not just in the act of writing,but also in the sealing, the stamp-hunting and the tramp to the post box.  By its very essence, this labour constitutes a form of compliment to the recipient.  And it is no coincidence, surely, that condolences are still, for the most part, written the old-fashioned way.  Sorrow deserves a weight that only pen and paper can supply.  As do some joys: a heartfelt thank-you, the birth of a child, a wedding.

So, while cooperating with the technological revolution - and indeed trying to capitalise on it  - I tweet! I blog! I have a facebook page!  - I have for a while now been harbouring a general sadness about what I perhaps lazily regarded as  the demise of the written word.  Until it dawned on me that there is nothing to mourn.  For, not only are all modes of correspondence still available - an expanding feast of electronic options being added to the more traditional ones -  but the written word itself has never been less under threat.  Indeed, it is proliferating...running rampant like that Japanese pond weed we are supposed to be afraid of.  Texts, emails, tweets, ipads, social networking sites, chat rooms, online clubs, blogs...  As a writer, I am aware of never having been under greater pressure to produce sentence-fodder beyond the delivery of an actual novel.  But it's not just writers, it's everyone.  Words, words words.  The entire human race is feverishly writing, more messages, more letters, more opinions, more news.  Perhaps, one day soon, it will be the health of the spoken word that we are worried about.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>104</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2012-10-28 17:29:30</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2012-10-28 17:29:30</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>closed</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>october-post</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="newsletters"><![CDATA[Newsletters]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[3]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_jd_tweet_this</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[yes]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_jd_target</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[http://amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=104]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_jd_goo</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[http://goo.gl/kZYBf]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_jd_wp_twitter</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:1:{i:0;s:70:"I've just put a new post on my blog:  October Post http://goo.gl/kZYBf";}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
				<title>Author talks</title>
		<link>http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=110</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2012 12:57:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Amanda]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=110</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[Having a new book to promote means leaving one's desk to go to places and talk to people.  Writing stories is not enough.  These days authors have to help 'sell' them.  Part of me wants to complain.  I am a writer, not a salesperson.  If I had wanted to be a salesperson I would have gone into Sales and Marketing.  I get stressed out about what to wear and what to say.   Of course I think the story in my novel is compelling or I wouldn't have written it.  But it seems arrogant somehow to set about trying to persuade everyone else of that view.  Then there is the even greater worry that NO ONE WILL COME TO LISTEN ANYWAY.  Even ticketed events are not a guarantee of bums on seats.  People buy tickets on gusts of good intentions and interest, only to realise as the date approaches, that it is Aunt Agatha's eightieth or there's something good on the telly.  If it is not a ticketed event the terror is all  the greater.  A terror one tries to mask, clutching one's notes in front of the empty rows as the clock ticks towards the advertised start of one's speech.  My highest head-count is a hundred (ish).  My lowest is five.  (It was a library event on a dank evening and at least one of the attendees was simply seeking shelter from the cold.)

But then - always - I realise it doesn't matter.  The terror melts.  An audience at a book event, whether it comprises two, twenty two or a hundred and two, is an audience of people who are interested in books.  They want to hear what one has to say.  They ask good questions afterwards.  I am always sorry when it is over.  Always.  I leave happy and humbled.  Back at my desk something changes too.  I feel reinvigorated, as if my imaginative muscle has been refreshed.  Part of it is the effect if a holiday from the coalface. The other, better part is the renewed sense of connection with the world of reading.  Actors need audiences. Novelists just need the sense of being read.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>110</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2012-12-06 12:57:27</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2012-12-06 12:57:27</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>closed</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>author-talks</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="newsletters"><![CDATA[Newsletters]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[3]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_jd_tweet_this</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[yes]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_jd_target</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[http://amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=110]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_jd_goo</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[http://goo.gl/bFXBc]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_jd_wp_twitter</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:1:{i:0;s:70:"I've just put a new post on my blog:  Author talks http://goo.gl/bFXBc";}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
				<title>December Deliberations</title>
		<link>http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=114</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 23 Dec 2012 18:18:48 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Amanda]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=114</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[Each December I resolve to stay healthy and relaxed  in the run-up to Christmas.  It is just a case - I tell myself - of maintaining the right attitude, keeping perspective, not letting the festive season <em>loom</em>; not letting it become the deadline for absolutely everything, quite apart from the mandatory production of cooked turkeys and wrapped gifts.  But loom it does.  Deadlines abound.   And then I fall ill.  Last year it was a chest infection and tennis elbow (both arms...er....lots of shopping).  The year before it was flu (and I mean REAL flu where you are in bed for 10 days and simply want to die).  The year before that was one of the snowy ones and my back 'went' thanks to shoveling the drive.  This year has topped all its predecessors however, in the form of the presentation of that decidedly un-festive and curiously named disease, Shingles.  Which, for those who do not know, is chicken pox (in all its glory), followed by neuralgia, which basically means your skin hurts. Even clothes on your skin hurt.  Oh yes, it's been a cracking December.

But there have been silver linings.  Like time on a sofa with books and the telly and cups of tea.  Time, in other words, to feed slothful addictions with the minimum of guilt.  I have eaten a lot of chocolate and caught up on all my taped episodes of Downton, The Killing and Homeland.  I have also watched, avidly, the final rounds of the two big TV winter talent shows.  Like most people I thought Strictly beat the X Factor by some distance, but I would also say that both competitions shared one interesting thing in common.  And that is:  No matter how good contestants are in the early weeks, or in middle rounds, or later on; when it comes to clinching victory it is <em>only</em> the final performance that counts.  Something 'extra' is required for it too; something that renders the  'back list'  of songs/dances, no matter how brilliant, wholly irrelevant.  Which is why the X Factor judges had to fight so hard - and so obviously - to keep the talented James Arthur safe, and why Louis Smith saw off the brilliant Denise Van Outen last night.  She had been consistently and staggeringly impressive, week after week - a true, performing 'artist'.  Louis on the other hand, had been a genius gymnast, going through the motions of dance.  But in that final performance something happened.  An alchemy took place; a perfect fusion between the gymnast in him and the dancer.  The effect was sublime.  It made me very happy.  It put me thoroughly in the mood for Christmas.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>114</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2012-12-23 18:18:48</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2012-12-23 18:18:48</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>closed</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>december-deliberations</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="newsletters"><![CDATA[Newsletters]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[3]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_jd_tweet_this</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[yes]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_jd_target</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[http://amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=114]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_jd_goo</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[http://goo.gl/v3UMj]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_jd_wp_twitter</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:1:{i:0;s:80:"I've just put a new post on my blog:  December Deliberations http://goo.gl/v3UMj";}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
				<title>THE LOVE CHILD</title>
		<link>http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=120</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2013 16:48:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Amanda]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=120</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[Today sees the publication of my new novel, The Love Child.  It makes me happy to write that, happier still to see my labours bound so beautifully and available for public consumption.  But there are other trickier feelings floating around too.  Such as a mild sense of anticlimax (it takes so <em>long </em>to reach this point!), and nervousness as to how it will be received.  Because The Love Child, like all my books (this is my 15th), has a small piece of my own heart in it, and I know only too well that the world can be a cruel and critical place.

Oddest of all on publication day, however, is the dim sense of detachment that accompanies it.  This is partly because the production process demands months of objectivity - there are jacket options to mull over, blurbs to write, publicity ideas to kick around, launch events to organise.  No wonder then, that by the time the novel is pushed out into the world it has started to feel inherently separate and independent from the scribbling hopes that began two years ago.  But more than that, every author learns that a certain letting-go is necessary, just as parents have, at some stage to dare to grant freedom to their offspring.  The work has been done.  It only remains for the 'fruit' of that work to be set free, to sink, or swim, or (most likely!) paddle around, according to its own strengths.  I might have written The Love Child, but as its creator I am now largely irrelevant.  It is my new work-in-progress that needs me now (page 99 at the last count).  So I am going to turn my attentions to that....but not till after spot of champagne...possibly even quite a lot.

For those that buy The Love Child, I thank you and wish you well.  I hope it gives you something....entertainment, pleasure, maybe a little pain.  But don't come crying to me if it doesn't.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>120</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2013-01-17 16:48:49</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2013-01-17 16:48:49</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>closed</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>the-love-child</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="newsletters"><![CDATA[Newsletters]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[3]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_jd_target</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[http://amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=120]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_jd_tweet_this</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[yes]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_jd_goo</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[http://goo.gl/IN27y]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_jd_wp_twitter</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:1:{i:0;s:76:"I've just put a new post on my blog:  THE LOVE CHILD http://goo.gl/IN27y #fb";}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
				<title>Love vs Duty</title>
		<link>http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=122</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov -0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Amanda]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=122</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[I had two treats last week - Manet at the RA and Onegin (the ballet) at the ROH. Sometimes (if you're me) you get to the point of heading off to such things and wonder why you are bothering.....peering through crowds at paintings and people in tights....WHY?  And then (if you're me), you go and find yourself bowled over, gobsmacked, humbled, happy but in pieces.  Manet married his mistrewanting to steal at least three paintings to keep with you FOREVER because they make your heart swell with the joy of being on the planet (that was in the RA) and reduced to tears I was close to tears by the end of both.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>122</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2013-02-13 17:37:27</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>closed</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>draft</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="newsletters"><![CDATA[Newsletters]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[3]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_jd_tweet_this</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[yes]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
				<title>Love Matters</title>
		<link>http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=124</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2013 11:29:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Amanda]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=124</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[Every so often (not just on Valentines Day) I am struck, all over again, by the astonishing reach and drive of human love.  The Technological Revolution, Wars, Famines, Rockets On The Moon and Melting Ice-Caps...this non-stop backdrop of epic, game-changing events continues, often at breakneck speed, changing our world.  And yet it is still the abstraction we call Love that beams mostly fiercely in our daily lives, the thing most of us seek to experience and understand.  It brings down Generals, Politicians, smitten teachers, smitten teenagers, and everything in between.  It is the engine of all that is saintly and selfless, as well as much that is satanic and selfish.  I know I sound dramatic, but it is dramatic.  The endless human quest to love and be loved in return. It trips us up but is also what keeps us going.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>124</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2013-02-14 11:29:53</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2013-02-14 11:29:53</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>closed</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>love-matters</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="newsletters"><![CDATA[Newsletters]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[3]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_jd_target</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[http://amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=124]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_jd_tweet_this</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[yes]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_jd_goo</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[http://goo.gl/X1eFD]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_jd_wp_twitter</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:1:{i:0;s:74:"I've just put a new post on my blog:  Love Matters http://goo.gl/X1eFD #fb";}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
				<title>It&#039;s not so bad! </title>
		<link>http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=127</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 12:11:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Amanda]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=127</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[It is hard not to be gloomy at the moment, don't you find?  For Brits it is always hard, but what with the "triple-dip recession" imminent (does that mean the double-dip is finished....???!!), dumps of wall-high snow landing across the country, crushing limp frost-bitten daffodils and necessitating the rescue of pensioners, it is especially difficult.  With friends, shopkeepers, cabbies, blogs....our national Licence To Moan has never been stronger.

BUT I have some perspective for you.  It comes from the life of the poet John Keats, about whom I have been reading in Nicholas Roe's stunning biography.  Here are some facts. I think they speak for themselves.

By the age of twenty two Keats had lost many close members of his family, including his father, his mother and his beloved brother Tom, whom he nursed to his death from consumption over months and months, realising in the process that his own intermittent sore throat and chest trouble probably meant a similar, premature end awaited him too.

It did, when he was 25 years old.

Keats was a qualified doctor as well as a great poet.  He knew that avoiding cold bitter weather was paramount to staying healthy.  But during the last three years of his life the English winters were especially harsh, with FREEZING TEMPERATURES LASTING THROUGH MARCH.  Keats, reliant on walking everywhere, (due largely to cock-ups with wills, wrangles and sheer bad luck, he lived in a state of near-constant penury) splashed out on new thicker shoes and a warmer coat.  But it was too late.  His chest troubles worsened.  Within two months of Tom's death, he was chronically ill himself.  An infection the following winter saw him coughing blood.  He fought on, but it was clear he was dying.  A last ditch effort to see off the illness by moving from the dank cruel London winter of 1820-21 to the relatively balmier climes of Rome, failed.  After months of excruciating pain, he died on February 23rd 1821, far from home, with only one of his many friends at his side.

During the course of those last years he managed to write some of the greatest Romantic poetry in the history of English literature.

Oh yes, he was also in love with, and engaged to, a woman whom he could not touch for fear of making her ill too.

So when my son (aged 24) muttered a complaint this weekend about the golf course being shut due to bad weather, I mentioned some of the above facts.

I keep thinking about them too.   Perspective.  I find it really really helps.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>127</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2013-03-25 12:11:19</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2013-03-25 12:11:19</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>closed</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>its-not-so-bad</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="newsletters"><![CDATA[Newsletters]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_jd_target</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[http://amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=127]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_jd_tweet_this</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[yes]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_jd_goo</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[http://goo.gl/WA0rT]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_jd_wp_twitter</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:1:{i:0;s:78:"I've just put a new post on my blog:  It's not so bad! http://goo.gl/WA0rT #fb";}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
				<title>One Great (Virtual) Leap Forward</title>
		<link>http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=131</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2013 12:30:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Amanda]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=131</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[I have decided that the British seasons are like one of those fairground Big Dipper rides....tantalisingly sluggish to the top of a steep climb (that's winter), then whizzing down the slope on the other side (that's May-Oct) at a hundred times the speed. We are in that whizzing bit now and I want it to slow down.  I don't know where April went.  It passed in a blink.  I got drunk on all that sunshine.  I did things like GARDENING. (I never garden). I also, finally, mustered the confidence (the sun has multifarious beneficial effects) to acquire my first IPHONE.  It is the very latest model, sleek and white and I know it is just a question of time before I sit on it or drop it.  Until then, it has produced several radical changes to my humdrum life.  Namely:

1. I get glances of respect from my twentysomething sons, wondering if I might not be a Lost Cause after all.

2. I embark on car journeys to new places without the terror of getting lost.

3. I can listen to the latest Bruno Mars single (it is the only track I have downloaded) at any time, though doing so does tend to interrupt those glances of filial respect (see above).

4.  Most significantly of all, I have downloaded a book onto it.  ME - downloaded a BOOK!  Now.  I have <em>nothing </em>against downloads, kindles or any other aspect of e-publishing....how can an author NOT want her books to be enjoyed in all forms possible??!!!  But I have made no secret of the fact that I still prefer to read the hard versions, for reasons which I know many romantic traditionalists share with me: Books smell nice.  They are enjoyable to hold and handle.  They develop character.  They are containers and triggers for all the memories of life lived during the course of the reading.  They look very fine on shelves, especially (in my view) if visibly a little beaten up from the attention they have received.

So, in the small world of this writer, downloading a book onto an iphone 5 is something of a momentous event.  I haven't read the work in question yet. It is, shall we say, a very "commercial" title,  picked primarily out of competitive curiosity, not something I expect to want to keep on a shelf for reasons of posterity or anything else.  But I like the 'virtual' look of it, sitting on the 'virtual' shelf, behind the little icon of an open book.  It's neat and natty.  I shall save it for a long train journey when I have finished the crossword and don't want to disturb the person sitting next to me by rummaging for more solid reading matter.  It's like having a  glossy magazine still in its plastic wrapper, or a snack to ward off a future attack of the munchies.  Yes, I am very happy to have taken possession of my first virtual book.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>131</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2013-05-10 12:30:39</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2013-05-10 12:30:39</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>closed</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>one-great-virtual-leap-forward</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="newsletters"><![CDATA[Newsletters]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[3]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_jd_tweet_this</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[yes]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_jd_goo</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[http://goo.gl/fwZLk]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_jd_target</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[https://www.googleapis.com/urlshortener/v1/url?key=AIzaSyBSnqQOg3vX1gwR7y2l-40yEG9SZiaYPUQ]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_jd_wp_twitter</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:1:{i:0;s:94:"I've just put a new post on my blog:  One Great (Virtual) Leap Forward http://goo.gl/fwZLk #fb";}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
				<title>The Fox Cub</title>
		<link>http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=134</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2013 14:59:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Amanda]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=134</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[I first spotted the cub about a month ago.  I know, I know, urban foxes are disease-carrying vermin (and they terrorize my cats), but it looked irresistibly dear, curled up into a glossy ball in the sunshine next to its scrawny Mum.  They spent the afternoon dozing and nibbling fleas off each other, and I thought how sweet, and tried to work rather than watch.

Then it stood up.  Or tried to.  It's back legs were pitiable - two useless trailing stumps, from a birth defect, it looked like, or perhaps an early, fleeting, violent encounter with the wheel of a passing car.  To watch the little thing try and walk broke my heart.  It looked like a tiny wheelbarrow with no one to push it.  I was so distraught I tweeted about it (a relatively rare event).  I was certain that within days the cub would die or be killed, making horrible, handy carrion for big birds.  Because London might be urban, but that makes it no less of a jungle for the wild animals that inhabit it.  I consulted friends, mulled over cruel-to-be-kind issues and whether to call the RSPCA.   In the end I did nothing.

But the cub and its Mum reappeared.  And it had got the hang of walking!  Somehow (those of you who are squeamish look away now) the trailing back legs had sort of....hardened into what I can only describe as 'support sticks'.  Crucially, this meant that there was some balance and ballast for it to get around - wheelbarrow-style - very-nicely-thank-you. The pair took up daily residence on the back lawn.  As time went by the cub's upper body strength grew visibly impressive, like the torso of a wheelchair user who lifts weights.  The Mum remained scrawny (no hair on her tail - eek!) but was as attentive and protective as ever of her half-broken offspring.  I got used to seeing them.  I stopped worrying.  I reported proudly to friends on the little creature's progress.

And then suddenly, a couple of days ago, they didn't come.  A big burly fox was lying in their spot instead.  It has been there ever since, lolling and snapping at flies, looking pleased with itself, looking like a bully.  The sort of bully who would run a single mum and its handicapped offspring out of town.  Or worse...

I know I'm I just a novelist, who makes up stories.  And they are just foxes.

But then again, all lives are stories.  Every existence, animal or human, has a beginning, a middle and an end.  And in the process each creature will encounter tragedies, like mutilated legs, and joys, like sunshine and caring Mums.

The novelist's job is to notice and to write the stories down.

&nbsp;]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>134</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2013-06-20 14:59:39</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2013-06-20 14:59:39</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>closed</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>the-fox-cub</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="newsletters"><![CDATA[Newsletters]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[3]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_jd_tweet_this</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[yes]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_jd_goo</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[http://goo.gl/fwZLk]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_jd_target</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[https://www.googleapis.com/urlshortener/v1/url?key=AIzaSyBSnqQOg3vX1gwR7y2l-40yEG9SZiaYPUQ]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_jd_wp_twitter</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:1:{i:0;s:73:"I've just put a new post on my blog:  The Fox Cub http://goo.gl/fwZLk #fb";}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
				<title>If you are struggling in the July heat:</title>
		<link>http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=142</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2013 15:50:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Amanda]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=142</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[I make a point never to complain about hot weather in the UK.  EVER.

For those who may be struggling to stay positive, here are 10 of my reasons why the heatwave is a Wonderful Thing:

1. The faint but indelible feeling of being...On Holiday!

2. It takes about one minute to get dressed in the mornings.  T-shirt, shorts, flip-flops.  Job Done. (More time in bed).

3. The butter is soft-soft.  Easier to spread on bread.  Less gets used.  Healthier!

4. The chink of cutlery across the garden fence....your neighbours exist! They are happy sun-seekers just like you!

5. EATING OUTSIDE, even at night, without the need of a fleece and thick socks. (Socks might be required against the midges, but I prefer <em>Off! -</em> fine so long as one remembers to wash one's hands before dipping into the crisps/nuts/dips accompanying the pre-prandial drink.

6. Prosecco.  The evening heat demands it. (With snacks.  See above).

7. Flowers at dusk (ie 9pm), velvet and vibrant after absorbing the belting heat of the afternoon.

8. The weather pundits can still be gloriously WRONG. Back in early June I seem to recall a prediction of wet summers for THIRTY YEARS.

9. Summer berries all taste as they are supposed to, even supermarket ones: sweet and full of sun.  I am eating several kilos a week. (Healthy!)

10.  It's only JULY!  By the time the heatwave breaks many of us will still have our 'real' summer holidays to look forward to.

(Mine's a week in Spain. I hope it doesn't rain).]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>142</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2013-07-16 15:50:11</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2013-07-16 15:50:11</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>closed</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>if-you-are-struggling-in-the-july-heat</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="newsletters"><![CDATA[Newsletters]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[3]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_jd_tweet_this</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[yes]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_jd_goo</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[http://goo.gl/fwZLk]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_jd_target</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[https://www.googleapis.com/urlshortener/v1/url?key=AIzaSyBSnqQOg3vX1gwR7y2l-40yEG9SZiaYPUQ]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_jd_wp_twitter</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:1:{i:0;s:101:"I've just put a new post on my blog:  If you are struggling in the July heat: http://goo.gl/fwZLk #fb";}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>4</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[max]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email></wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url>http://%/efhfdfji46</wp:comment_author_url>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>188.168.86.74</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2014-11-14 09:24:54</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2014-11-14 09:24:54</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[<strong><a href="http://trustedpillspot.com/?p=777&amp;lol= trusted@pillspot.com" rel="nofollow">.</a></strong>

thanks for information.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>0</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type>trackback</wp:comment_type>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
	</item>
	<item>
				<title>September &amp; Dickens</title>
		<link>http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=144</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2013 11:21:29 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Amanda]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=144</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[My summer reading bonanza produced two stand-out favourites: Elizabeth Strout's <em>The Burgess Boys </em>and Colum McCann's <em>Transatlantic.</em> (I am glancing at them now, sitting in the books-I-have-loved bit of my bookshelf, looking worn and warm, old friends, begging to be revisited.  Do I need to offer any other reason why, for me, a Kindle still holds no appeal?!)

But now it is September and the days are shorter and cooler and I have started on Claire Tomalin's biography of Dickens, which has been gathering dust in the pile next to my bed since last Christmas.  I don't know what I expected.  I thought I knew something about Dickens.  Of course, I must do.  I have read (nearly) all his novels, written essays on them, studied their tragicomic genius and the sometimes imperfect effect of a writer trying to balance a social conscience with his artistic integrity (...er...Hard Times would be the best example of that). I have discussed TV adaptations of them round dinner tables and merrily promoted the notion of Dickens as our earliest 'Soap Opera Writer', a master at keeping his audiences on tenterhooks for each weekly instalment (the bulk of Dickens' novels were written in serial form).  So maybe I was hoping for some sort of grand overview, the joining up of a few loose dots.

Instead, I find that I am gripped - thanks to Claire Tomalin's skill - by the light cast on the day-to-day tensions of Charles Dickens as a <em>writer.  </em>I do not mean to sound presumptuous, but I am only too familiar with these tensions. When readers ask me what it is like to write novels I always confess that it is mostly...horrible: a roller-coaster of hope and despair, trial and error, insecurity and confidence, interlaced with occasional - very occasional - patches of sublime, flowing, joy.  Then there are the money worries, which never sit happily next to creativity; not to mention the ups and downs of one's personal life - a sea of interruption against which I throw ineffectual sandbags every day.

Somehow, I hadn't expected Charles Dickens, prolific genius, globally successful in his own time, to have gone through the same daily hurdles.  But he did.  His writing stressed him out constantly - the deadlines, the need to be at his best, the demands of publicity, which were quite as intense as those thrown at many celebrities today.  Added to which, his personal life was mired in problems, from his bankrupt sponging father to a wife who, through no fault of her own, could not given him the spark of intimate reciprocity for which he longed.  And yet he produced the work that he did, at the rate that he did, achieving the quality that he did.  It makes the achievement all the more extraordinary.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>144</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2013-09-09 11:21:29</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2013-09-09 11:21:29</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>closed</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>september-dickens</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="newsletters"><![CDATA[Newsletters]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[3]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_jd_tweet_this</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[yes]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_jd_goo</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[http://goo.gl/fwZLk]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_jd_target</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[https://www.googleapis.com/urlshortener/v1/url?key=AIzaSyBSnqQOg3vX1gwR7y2l-40yEG9SZiaYPUQ]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_jd_wp_twitter</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:1:{i:0;s:81:"I've just put a new post on my blog:  September & Dickens http://goo.gl/fwZLk #fb";}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
				<title>Halloween Confession</title>
		<link>http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=156</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2013 16:26:46 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Amanda]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=156</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[I am not a fan of Halloween.  Sorry.  But there it is.

To be specific, what I am really not a fan of is the dubious tradition of 'Trick or Treating'.  I first came across it while living in America in the early nineties.  My sons were then aged two and four and I simply could not see the appeal of taking them out in the cold dark streets to knock on the doors of strangers and ask for sweets.  But I was given little choice.  In the USA Halloween hype starts many weeks in advance of the date, and is backed by adults as well as children, commerce and the media, comprising a bombardment so widespread and intense that there was - and is - simply no avoiding it.  My two were as excited as every other toddler in the country. Costumes got cobbled together.  Strangers' doors got knocked on. Copious amounts of 'candy' got handed out and eaten.  I hid my lack of enthusiasm as best I could, taking secret consolation from the fact that this was, plainly, an AMERICAN mania.  Once we were back living in the UK, it would all be done with.

Ha ha ha.

Because sometime around our return to London a couple of years later, Halloween Hype seemed to make its own parallel journey across the Atlantic.  That meant I had another TWELVE(ish) YEARS of all the nonsense to endure: The last minute production of costumes (not my area of creative strength), face-paint application (I am better at this), door-stepping strangers, and the accumulation of enough sweets to last a year, let alone a single day.  There was sometimes a darker side to the nonsense too - toxic rubbish thrown at the house, lovingly made garden decorations smashed (I was particularly upset about the pumpkin-lanterns), and marauding gangs of decidedly OLD 'children', intimidating the much younger enthusiasts, not to mention their parents...

Oh yes, I have done my Halloween Time.

So now I say YA-BOO-SUCKS to the whole Show.  This year there won't be any hopeful goblins on my doorstep (too-old or otherwise) because all house-lights visible to the roadside will be turned OFF.  I shall be tucked safely out of sight in my back room, curled up on the sofa with  a glass of Malbec, the Times crossword and the telly. I've got a feast of catching up to do - Homeland, Downton, Boardwalk Empire...a second glass of Malbec might even be required. If the doorbell is rung I won't budge.  I shall feel a tad guilty, (I am not an automaton), but learning how to please oneself is one of the great consolations of getting older.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>156</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2013-10-30 16:26:46</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2013-10-30 16:26:46</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>closed</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>halloween-confession</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="newsletters"><![CDATA[Newsletters]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[3]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_jd_tweet_this</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[yes]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_jd_url</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=156]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_jd_target</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=156]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_jd_wp_twitter</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:1:{i:0;s:108:"I've just put a new post on my blog:  Halloween Confession http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=156 #fb";}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
				<title>December Digital LAUNCH News!</title>
		<link>http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=163</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2013 10:51:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Amanda]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=163</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<strong>December 6th: Digital Publication Day for my novels 'Relative Love' and 'A Family Man':</strong>

&nbsp;

<strong><a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/dp/B00H2GYBVO">http://www.amazon.co.uk/dp/B00H2GYBVO</a></strong>

<strong><a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/dp/B00H2GYBP0">http://www.amazon.co.uk/dp/B00H2GYBP0</a></strong>

&nbsp;

I can dimly - very dimly - remember when I thought 'digital publishing' wasn't going to be something that would affect me too much....ha ha ha.

I never was any good at reading global trends.  It was one of the reasons why I knew it was a wise decision to leave my first career in advertising.  In fact, you are reading words written by an Account Manager who, when asked to help pitch for a new product called 'decaffinated coffee', (it was Hag, circa 1983), announced many times (quite loudly) to anyone prepared to listen: "Coffee WITHOUT caffeine? Like that's ever going to catch on..."

I had a business computer client too, whom I would secretly scoff at for his claim that one day - in our life time - there would be a 'personal' computer in every home....

My excuse is that I have other talents.  Like writing novels.

And now I couldn't be happier that was wrong!  Because two of the books of which I am most proud and fond (first published by Hodder &amp; Stoughton in 2001 and 2004 respectively) are being given a Second Chance to find readers who will love them and 'get' them and not mind at all that I am the sort of person who can't spot a national trend even when it hits me over the head.  Novelists write to be read.  And so a day when a story is launched at the world is a Special Day - not so much like the launch of a ship, I always think, so much as a message in a bottle, bobbing off on its own, hopefully to be scooped up by Someone who will understand and be absorbed by the gentle and loving spirit in which it was sent forth.

So I say: Good Luck  'Relative Love' and 'A Family Man'.  You are part of my brood and I wish you well.  I shall drink a little champagne, and get on with the next.

&nbsp;]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>163</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2013-12-06 10:51:21</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2013-12-06 10:51:21</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>closed</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>december-digital-launch-news</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="newsletters"><![CDATA[Newsletters]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[3]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_jd_tweet_this</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[yes]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_jd_url</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=163]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_jd_target</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=163]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_jd_wp_twitter</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:1:{i:0;s:117:"I've just put a new post on my blog:  December Digital LAUNCH News! http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=163 #fb";}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
				<title>new post</title>
		<link>http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=17</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2012 09:22:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=17</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[new]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>17</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2012-07-11 09:22:39</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2012-07-11 09:22:39</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>new-post</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>trash</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[2]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
				<title>Machine Love</title>
		<link>http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=170</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2014 12:14:06 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Amanda]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=170</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[I have fallen in love.  With a car.  This is not something I would have expected of myself, not just because I am an unabashed, problematical, die-hard Romantic, in the most conventional 'human' sense, but because I don't like machines.  So I have been trying to analyse the reasons why:

1. Apart from a £400 beaten-up old black Ford Something (containing a supersonic engine that someone had inserted for a laugh) which I bought with my Life Savings aged 18, and which lasted for a princely 5 months before being towed off for scrap (mistakenly, but then I thought, yeah, good idea), this new Love of my Life is the FIRST CAR I HAVE EVER PURCHASED ENTIRELY ON MY OWN.                                                                                                           Conclusion: A late-bloom exultation in the power to choose.

2. My new love is very beautiful - shiny sleek charcoal with a silver trim.  It doesn't have many miles on the clock and is only ONE AND A HALF YEARS OLD!    (All previous (jointly) purchased cars have been...er...quite old.)       Conclusion: A shallow falling-fall-for-appearances.

3. The boot opens if you press and hold a button on the car key.  Pressing another button closes it.  I am very keen on this function.  Indeed, I LOVE this function.  Maybe because I have a bad back (as most writers do).  Maybe because the boot of my previous car required what I shall call <em>wrestling.</em><em>                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                         </em>Conclusion: Not seeing the wood for the trees.  Being 'blinded' by the trees, one might say.

4. This car works!!!!!!!!! For decades (ask any friends) previous aforementioned (quite old) cars often....didn't work - breakdowns, seizures, bits falling off, I could write a novel entitled 'Car Disasters'.  The real sadness of the tale being that even the smoothly functioning periods were never enjoyable because I knew they wouldn't last.  Because, in other words, I had no <em>faith </em>in the vehicles.                                                                                                                                      Conclusion: I love this car because I have faith in it.

In summary then: Surprise. Exultation. Physical attraction. Blindness.  Faith.

I told you it was Love.

&nbsp;]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>170</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2014-01-25 12:14:06</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2014-01-25 12:14:06</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>closed</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>machine-love</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="newsletters"><![CDATA[Newsletters]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[3]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_jd_tweet_this</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[yes]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_jd_url</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=170]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_jd_target</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=170]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_jd_wp_twitter</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:1:{i:0;s:100:"I've just put a new post on my blog:  Machine Love http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=170 #fb";}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
				<title>Choosing Books</title>
		<link>http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=173</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 09 Mar 2014 19:55:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Amanda]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=173</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[My current "house-mate" (aka: Job-hunting Graduate Son) recently remarked that I always 'rave' about whatever book I happen to be reading.  He did not intend the observation as a compliment...it was more of  a how-dull-bibliophile-mothers-are type statement.  I immediately told him he was wrong (always a pleasure) and drummed up a couple of titles that had disappointed me, including - shock-horror - Richard Ford's 'The Sportswriter' which I think I simply found depressing....at a time in my life when I really wasn't in the mood to be depressed.  (And no, that is not an obvious thing to say, because different books suit different moods and stages of one's life.  One of the many pleasures of reading is the way a particular story can land in one's lap like a gift, arriving, as if by the twitch of some divine wand, at precisely the moment it is 'needed'.)

But the conversation with the house-mate got me thinking about How/Why I Choose Books.  I came to the following conclusions:

1. There is something about a Critically Acclaimed Global Bestseller that makes me want to run in the opposite direction.  Particularly if it is called The Da Vinci Code, or Fifty Shades of Grey....I simply cannot bring myself to add to the sales of these commercial hot-cakes, not even out of curiosity.

2. More contrarily, even if the Global Bestseller is of a genre obviously up my street, there is a small obstinate worm inside my brain that makes me NOT want to buy it....at least not straight away.  I suppose it is to do with resisting the pull to become part of a stampeding herd.  I am not proud of this trait.  It has meant things like 'Wolf Hall' and 'The Book Thief ' took a while to get to.  Though boy, were they worth the wait.

3. Friends' recommendations.  I have learnt to be cautious of these.   Tastes vary so widely, and being a novelist complicates things - however one responds, there is a danger of being thought uppity or envious or self-promoting.  Even with friends known well enough to be beyond the reach of  such difficulties, confessing to not having enjoyed something that has been enthusiastically pushed one's way is not always easy.  Friends want to like each other's book recommendations.  It verifies and validates the friendship.  And though, of course, all differences of opinion should be aired and are fine, sometimes they are quite telling.<em> </em>  Like the person to whom I recommended a treasured favourite - Marilynne Robinson's 'Gilead' - only to be told, bluntly, disparagingly, how much it was hated.  I simply could not like the person quite as much afterwards.  I am sorry if that makes me shallow, I just couldn't.  I love the book and they were cruel about it.  A response to a book shows our sensibilities.  It does not lie.  It <em>can </em>matter.  So I am just as cautious about what I recommend to other people.

4. I have a sister whose choices I trust absolutely.  If she says a book will get under my skin, it always does.  She is busy and doesn't read as much fiction as me, but if she offers up a title then I leap on it.

5. I also trust my local bookseller, but for the opposite reason: He doesn't know me.  He also has broad, fine and eclectic tastes, which means he recommends books that never fail to surprise, delight and/or take me out of my comfort zone. It is thanks to him, for instance, that I read Yann Martell's letters to the Canadian Prime Minister.  A stunner.  (Warning: It's really hard to get hold of, even on Amazon, but worth hunting down).

6. My biggest trigger for purchasing a book, however, is a good review in a newspaper.  This never used to be the case.  Indeed, once upon a time reviews were for casting an occasional eye over, playing only a minimal role in the unhurried, enjoyable business of Deciding What To Read Next.  But these days time is so much shorter.  These days barely a week goes by when I don't take note of a book(s) that sounds worth adding to my bedside pile.  (There were three on Sunday alone...the George Eliot one, the Forster one, and the Kim Philby one, since you ask).

So yes, the Job-seeker is correct: I often 'rave' about my bedside reading-matter, but this is because each book has been selected with the greatest hope, the greatest care.   For what the job-seeker, at 23, does not yet know, is the extent to which Time gallops.  He does not know that one day he might wake up to the sobering realisation that there will simply not be enough hours in his life to read all the glorious books already published, let alone the ones yet to be written.  His mother certainly knows it.  It has made her more fussy, more focused but even more appreciative.

&nbsp;]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>173</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2014-03-09 19:55:13</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2014-03-09 19:55:13</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>closed</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>choosing-books</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="newsletters"><![CDATA[Newsletters]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[3]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_jd_tweet_this</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[yes]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_jd_url</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=173]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_jd_target</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=173]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_jd_wp_twitter</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:1:{i:0;s:102:"I've just put a new post on my blog:  Choosing Books http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=173 #fb";}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
				<title>Everyone has a novel in them....don&#039;t they?</title>
		<link>http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=176</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2014 10:02:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Amanda]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=176</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[Yes, of course Everyone 'has a novel in them'.  Because the lives of each and every one of us are 'stories' - narrative blends of the ordinary and the extraordinary, with happy bits and sad bits, and good bits and bad bits - there to be recounted through the written word to a wider audience, should the 'owner' of that 'narrative' choose.  And if someone else's life sounds more interesting, then you can just write about that one instead, can't you? Easy peasy.

Till you try it.

People who haven't tried it like to corner novelists with conversational gambits like:  'Hey, here's something for your next book...just listen to this, you won't believe it....'  They then launch into an anecdote - or life-story! - in the belief that they are handing over an invaluable 'free' gift.  Or (worse), they nod at the disclosure that one writes fiction for a living and then remark that they are thinking of writing their own life story one day.  As if it is merely shortage of time that is preventing them from bashing out a bestseller.

I am sorry if  I sound obnoxious.  In fact during such conversations I always aim to be as encouraging as I can.   'Great,' I say, 'just do it!  Start, then finish.  Spit it out.  Get it down.'  This is not just because I have been raised to behave politely, but because I genuinely hope that I might be standing in front of the next Hemingway or Eliot.  Nothing would make me happier.

The truth is, telling a story well, and compellingly, sustaining momentum and interest over a couple of hundred pages or so, is (for most of us), a hard act to pull off.  Sheer grind is the key - trial and error, sticking at it, not to mention ruthless self-editing.  Making it harder is the fact that the best novels don't <em>just </em>tell a story; they also, through that story, cast original and interesting spotlights on the business of being human.  To me this is what makes writing a good novel so difficult, and reading a good novel so breathtaking.  I love stories that make me sit up and see the world a little differently, or which put the finger on something I have half felt or half thought or half feared. Some writers lob such nuggets out all the time.  Others make you wait until the end.  Like Dorothy Whipple in her wonderful novel 'Someone At A Distance' ,where she holds you in thrall with pure story-telling until the final page, and then gives you this:

<em>She had learnt to wait for the changes and the help that life brings.  Life is like the sea, sometimes you are in the trough of the wave, sometimes on the crest.  When you are in the trough, you wait for the crest, and always, trough or crest, a mysterious tide bears you forward to an unseen but certain shore.</em>

To me this is wisdom.  And comfort. It is why I loved the novel.  It is also, I believe (she is not around to contradict me) why Dorothy Whipple wrote the novel.  She crafted a brilliant narrative, but the above sentences were what she truly set out to 'say'.

&nbsp;

(If you want to know more, check out my review: https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/173510.Amanda_Brookfield/blog)

&nbsp;]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>176</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2014-05-09 10:02:09</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2014-05-09 10:02:09</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>closed</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>everyone-has-a-novel-in-them-dont-they</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="newsletters"><![CDATA[Newsletters]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[3]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_jd_tweet_this</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[yes]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_jd_url</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=176]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_jd_target</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=176]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_jd_wp_twitter</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:1:{i:0;s:131:"I've just put a new post on my blog:  Everyone has a novel in them....don't they? http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=176 #fb";}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
				<title>The Value of Words</title>
		<link>http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=188</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 27 Jul 2014 15:21:23 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Amanda]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=188</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[My novel <strong>A Family Man</strong>, which took a year to write, is currently available to purchase for 99p.  This is thanks to an Amazon Summer Promotion and I couldn't be more pleased.  Last month, due to selection in a similar cut-price 24 hour deal, my book <strong>Relative Love </strong>rocketed from 125,000th to 12th in the Kindle Bestseller Rankings.  The next day it began its descent, but, oh my goodness, it was a giddy ride.  I sat glued to my screen watching the sale-bounce, whooping like a Wall Street trader.

The experience has sharpened my awareness of two things.

First, the power of Amazon.  The POWER of Amazon.  It is a behemoth.  For any writer wishing to sell books (and...er...that sort of goes with the territory...writers write to be <em>read</em>), Amazon is <em>the </em>global publisher, an awesome institution that must be courted, used, worked with, but never - NEVER - ignored.

Second, it got me thinking about the value of the written word.  99p is very small sum of money.  <strong>A Family Man </strong>took 365 days to write.  <strong>Relative Love </strong>took 730.  As a maths exercise the work-reward ratio is depressing.  I actually tried to do the sum but gave up, long division, especially when all the numbers come AFTER the decimal point, not being my idea of a fun-challenge.  But that is part of the point.  I am good with words not numbers.  I write books for a living.  I need the support of an industry with integrity to help me sell them.

Writing a novel is time-consuming and hard work.  This could be said of any writing, but novels, by and large, are <em>extra</em><em> </em>hard work because they contain tens of thousands of words, ideally packed with tricky things like Meaning and Surprise and Truth. I have yet to meet an author who finds the process a breeze.  Personally, I find it the opposite of a breeze.  In fact, every book for me is about the battle not to give up.  And even when that battle is won and the manuscript finished, I feel drained as opposed to celebratory, doubt-ridden, not to mention dumbfounded at how far the finished product has drifted from the original (for more glorious) conception.

I don't want violins.  I just want acknowledgement that 99p is not a lot.  Only a very few titles - the top millimetre of the Behemoth Publishing Pyramid - can hope to sell in sufficient numbers at such a price to make a humble - let alone a decent - living.

This means lots of good books won't get read.

Worse still, it means lots of good books won't get written.

To find out whether <strong>A Family Man </strong>should have slipped through the net, click here (for 99p): http://www.amazon.co.uk/A-Family-Man-Amanda-Brookfield-ebook/dp/B00H2GYBP0

&nbsp;]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>188</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2014-07-27 15:21:23</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2014-07-27 15:21:23</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>closed</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>the-value-of-words</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="newsletters"><![CDATA[Newsletters]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[3]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_jd_tweet_this</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[yes]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_jd_url</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=188]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_jd_target</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=188]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_jd_wp_twitter</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:1:{i:0;s:106:"I've just put a new post on my blog:  The Value of Words http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=188 #fb";}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
				<title>Creative Frictions</title>
		<link>http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=192</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2014 17:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Amanda]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=192</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[We all need something to push against.  It takes a few decades to realise this.  Growing up, our lives are structured by authority:

'Time to go to bed!'

'Time to wake up!'

'Time to get dressed!'

'Time to eat!'

'Do your homework!'

By our teens we are longing for the 'freedom' of independence.

Then 'freedom' comes and we realise we need to apply some structure to it or nothing gets done.  So we have to start shouting at ourselves when it's time to wake up and go to bed instead; what to eat and when to work - the voice in our heads is just as loud as any nagging parent.

This is one of the earliest and toughest lessons to learn as a writer.  I first discovered it when I left my busy London job to be a freelance journalist in Buenos Aires.  Hurrah! I thought: No more early alarm-calls!  No more idiotic clients!  No more tedious meetings!  I shall be my own boss.  I shall do what I like when I like.  But the dream of such freedom - of sitting around waiting for the inspirational mood to strike - dies fast.  Time, if one isn't careful, becomes a dead weight that needs carrying around.  It can become like living in slow-motion.  Nothing gets achieved, least of all anything creative.  One starts to miss not being chased up or called to account, even by idiotic clients.

Never have I written more efficiently than when my two sons were at nursery school.  I had a measly two hours at my desk a day  - TWO HOURS! - and boy did I throw myself into them.  I produced a book a year for seven years, much to the delight of my then publishers  My writing may have lacked a certain depth and not been as polished, but the time-friction definitely made me productive.

Since those days, I have learnt to relish the luxury of more time rather than being defeated by it, but different frictions have exerted their power instead.  Things like, Indecision, Dread, Indolence, Perfectionism, Fear of Failure...it is in fighting these that the alchemy of creativity has managed to assert itself to produce eight more novels.

But now (with novel 16) a new friction has come into play, the most 'creative' yet.  It's called RSI.  Thanks to so many hours at my desk this year, chiselling at the coal-face of my manuscript, my right shoulder has decided to adopt a position which, inconveniently, fires shooting pains down my right arm.  Horrible! Infuriating.  Painful.  I am writing this slowly, with breaks every couple of minutes to twiddle my wrists and windmill my arms.  I am having hours of weekly physio.  I am booked to see a Shoulder Specialist.  There is talk of injections.  Aaaaaaaaaaaaaaaagh.

And never - NEVER - have I been more eager to work.  I can hear the end of my novel in my head.  I know what it is about, where it is going, how to get it there...........those days of abstract distractions -  navel-gazing or watching the foxes in the garden  - are a distant memory.  ALL I WANT TO DO IS WRITE.  Perhaps, precisely because, for the first time in twenty five years, I can't.

I prefer the old type of frictions.  I want them back.  I'll never moan about them again.  I promise. When the RSI is cured, I am going to be the most grateful, efficient, productive novelist the world has ever seen.

&nbsp;

&nbsp;]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>192</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2014-10-19 17:00:52</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2014-10-19 17:00:52</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>closed</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>creative-frictions</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="newsletters"><![CDATA[Newsletters]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[3]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_jd_tweet_this</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[yes]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_jd_url</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=192]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_jd_target</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=192]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_jd_wp_twitter</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:1:{i:0;s:106:"I've just put a new post on my blog:  Creative Frictions http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=192 #fb";}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
				<title>Endings etc</title>
		<link>http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=201</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2014 18:34:08 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Amanda]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=201</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[A good ending is the hardest thing for a writer to pull off.  Readers can be swept along by fabulous narratives, full of twist and turn, but it is the final chapter  - the lingering taste in the mouth - against which a story will ultimately be judged. And rightly so.  It is the point where things come together - make sense - or fall apart.  A bad ending exposes the author as a fraud.  A good ending makes her/him seem like a magician.  A bad ending feels contrived, shallow, forgettable.  A good one manages unexpectedness, while, crucially, remaining true to all that has gone before. Its characters exit the stage, yet we feel as if they live on.

For me, this is why satisfaction with even the most ingenious seasonal TV series - Homeland et al - starts to pall.  There is never a proper 'ending'.  Instead, we are led a merry dance, teased, manipulated, towards yet another supposedly grand finale that is no more than a teeing up for the next year's serving of more-of-the-same.  It is like eating a bag of sweets - more-ish but ultimately un-satiating.  If a plot is endless then...................why should we care about it?

Real life, of course, offers few neat conclusions, teed up or otherwise.  We strive, we reach for things, and are constantly  blown off course.  Sometimes in small ways (cancelled trains, twisted ankles, lost passports), sometimes in vast ways (violence, love, illness).  And when it comes to our own endings (dignitas and suicide aside) we have least control of all, a powerlessness mirrored only by the unlookedfor matter of actually being born.  Birth, Death, they just happen.

And if I am honest, which, with age, I try increasingly to be, I am sure that some of the appeal of writing fiction is simply because it offers some sort of counterbalance to this uncertainty.  My novels may not be 'real life', but at least I am in charge. Endings may be fiendish to get right.  Characters may rebel, storming off down paths one had not envisaged and hurling out unexpected words.  But at least, when the chips are down, I retain the glorious power to rein them in, sort them out, brush them down and nudge them towards their destinies.

&nbsp;]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>201</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2014-12-22 18:34:08</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2014-12-22 18:34:08</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>closed</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>endings-etc</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="newsletters"><![CDATA[Newsletters]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[3]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_jd_twitter</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_jd_tweet_this</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[yes]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_jd_url</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=201]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_jd_target</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=201]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_jd_wp_twitter</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:1:{i:0;s:99:"I've just put a new post on my blog:  Endings etc http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=201 #fb";}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wpt_status_message</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Tweet sent successfully.]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
				<title>Writing vs Living</title>
		<link>http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=206</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2015 15:28:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Amanda]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=206</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[My mother died last week.  She was eighty one, and had had an amazing life, and was getting frail, so it was a blessedly sudden and speedy release for her, but a terrible shock for the rest of us.  Grief is a strange, exhausting business. It comes at you in waves over which you have no control.  Every time you think are okay to stand up it  knocks you down again.  And again.  The frequency of this reduces in time of course, but not always the intensity.  I know that with my father, who died fifteen years ago, I can still feel the loss of him like a hammer-blow to the back of the head.

So I was somewhat taken aback when a well-meaning acquaintance to whom I had broken the news about Mum said: 'Oh but this is the sort of thing you write about all the time isn't it'.  As if writing about  Love and Loss (which, yes,I do) might somehow lessen the punch of such dramas when they occur in my 'real' life.  I was kind to her.  I swallowed my tears.  I said I saw her point, but that writing about such things was like swimming, while experiencing them was like drowning.

Nora Ephron famously said of life's experiences that for a writer everything is 'grist to the mill'.  Yes, it can be.  But only after a process of fermentation and resurfacing and the protective, refracting prism of the imagination.  In the meantime the tsunami of real life hits the writer as hard as the next person.  Joy is joyous and pain hurts like fuck.  The shock of loss renders the mind blank.  On hearing that Mum was dying I couldn't even think how to open my front door.

Writing is tough.  But nothing like as tough as the business of being alive.

&nbsp;]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>206</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2015-02-04 15:28:32</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2015-02-04 15:28:32</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>closed</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>writing-vs-living</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="newsletters"><![CDATA[Newsletters]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[3]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_jd_twitter</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_jd_tweet_this</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[yes]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_jd_url</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=206]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_jd_target</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=206]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_jd_wp_twitter</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:1:{i:0;s:105:"I've just put a new post on my blog:  Writing vs Living http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=206 #fb";}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wpt_status_message</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Tweet sent successfully.]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
				<title>Milestones Matter</title>
		<link>http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=212</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2015 16:16:47 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Amanda]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=212</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[My son is leaving home.  Cue a chorus of jeers and "about-time-toos".  Forgive me if I don't join in.

They take their time to go, this lot, not like us oldsters, who packed our bags for a first job or uni and never looked back, apart from intermittent phone calls and the occasional festive visit.  No, this generation, for a variety of socio-economic reasons that I don't propose to go into here, have taken more time to flee the nest; and even when they do 'flee' they come back for prolonged spells, keeping in touch in between with emails and texts and instagrams and other more general demands upon one's time.  There are aspects of this that are not ideal.  But there are other, far more numerous aspects that are wonderful.  Like children and parents getting to know one another as adults, like getting extra help about the place, like having many many laughs that one wouldn't otherwise have had.  But then there comes a time when they really really leave, when, for all the conversations and connections ahead, an era has well and truly passed.

It is my youngest son who is going, so I have some 'previous' in the process, a fact that seems only to be adding to the intensity of the experience.  And when I say 'intensity' I do not mean that I am weeping and wailing and feeling abandoned (which I sort of am, but only in private - some things are not for subjection to anyone).  No, it is the vast milestone of what is taking place that strikes me hardest.  At whatever age it occurs, this is the equivalent of the bird toppling off the edge of the nest, to fall or fly depending on its own abilities.  The parent can shout /tweet (???) advice but the wee birdie must flap its own wings and if parents do too much interfering with this stage then nothing good transpires.

If I sound sad, it is because I am, a bit; but I am also excited for the son and rather proud.  I-would-say-this-wouldn't-I, but he is a fine young man.  Lots of important elements are in place.  He has a warm personality, a tremendous brain and a glorious sense of humour.  Best of all, he likes and reads other people with compassion and intelligence.  With luck - you always need luck - he will do well in life, and by that I refer not to money-making (which I think he will manage acceptably enough) but to the far more important and harder challenge of finding a path to happiness.  All I can do now is wait and watch and help if called upon to do so.

So.  A milestone indeed.  Just as much as turning twenty-one is a milestone, or getting married, or producing a child.  I wanted to tell the youngest all of this, especially the proud-parent-sentiments (he knows them, but it is still important sometimes to hear what you know), but not to overburden our farewell with the tears and general 'heaviness' that expressing such thoughts would inevitably generate.

So I have written him a letter.  A REAL letter.  On paper with ink, from a real fountain pen.  In it I have said everything I want to say.  He can read it in his own good time, without the burden of managing my response.  A letter has a weight to it, literally, more than any text or murmured words, half forgotten in weeks to come.  A letter goes into a drawer and continues to exist.  From time to time it gets found, dusted off, read again, re-treasured.

Yes, for some matters, still, only a letter will do.

&nbsp;]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>212</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2015-06-12 16:16:47</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2015-06-12 16:16:47</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>closed</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>milestones-matter</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="newsletters"><![CDATA[Newsletters]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[3]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_jd_twitter</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_jd_tweet_this</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[yes]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_jd_url</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=212]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_jd_target</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=212]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_jd_wp_twitter</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:1:{i:0;s:105:"I've just put a new post on my blog:  Milestones Matter http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=212 #fb";}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wpt_status_message</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Tweet sent successfully.]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
				<title>Why I Write </title>
		<link>http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=214</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2015 10:30:02 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Amanda]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=214</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[As many people know by now, I have finished my novel.  My 16th.  It is called 'The Distance Between Us' and has taken THREE YEARS to write, FOUR if you count the year before that when I was 'charging my batteries', or 'filling the well', or whatever euphemism you want for the business of <em>living life</em> for a bit instead of trying to write about it.  The length of time has many possible reasons: I have been getting divorced; my mother suddenly died.  Then a year ago I suffered a shoulder injury (it is impossible to write - with a pen or a keyboard - when you have a shoulder injury), which has still not fully healed.  But those excuses aside (they are good ones, you have to admit!), the plain fact is that writing novels is HARD and the more I write the HARDER THEY GET.

All of which has caused me to stop and consider why on earth I do it.  This is how the cycle goes, beginning with where I am now:

1. Finish novel.  Punch the air, but feel a touch desolate (you get attached to your novel).  Main emotion however is: I AM NEVER PUTTING MYSELF THROUGH THAT AGAIN. (Think Steve Redgrave, standing up in his boat after his 4th gold medal, not that I am comparing myself to the mighty SR, but you get the gist).  Set about telling friends and family that, though happy, you are NEVER PUTTING YOURSELF THROUGH THAT AGAIN.

2. Tinker with ms of completed novel in run-up to publication.  This can be quite fun.  The horrible bit is done.  The tinkering is fine-tuning.  The novel starts to feel  more separate - a completed object that happened to emerge from you rather than being painstakingly agonised over and crafted.  It starts, dare I say, to feel............inevitable.  Like it pre-existed and all you had to do was jot it down!  This is a dangerous and INCORRECT feeling.  You try to fight it, but you can't.

3.  Your life has entered a new phase.  You feel great!  Your bank account goes down more rapidly (because you have time to shop) but you are sleeping well a)Because you don't feel guilty that you are sleeping instead of writing b) Unworkable solutions for plot-glitches don't keeping pinging into your subconscious in the small hours.

4.  Then, one terrible day, you have an IDEA.  This may be triggered by reading......er.........Dostoevsky...but it is more likely to happen while browsing through 'Hello' or staring into space at a bus stop.

5.  You try to ignore the idea because it is so small and pointless and obvious - eg one sister nicks another sister's boyfriend.  But it niggles.

6.  Then the idea starts to grow tentacles.  One sister could be ugly, the other beautiful.  The boyfriend could be an old flame, getting in touch after years and years.  The sisters could have had a difficult childhood....

7.  You reach for your notebook, just to jot down the idea - get the tentacles out of your system.  But they start to get worse, more prolific, more complicated.

8.  Meanwhile, your last novel gets packaged and launched.  It looks nice!  You feel pleased and proud!  Fatally, you think, 'Well, that wasn't so hard, was it?'  Next time your agent calls you let slip that you are working on a new book.

And so it begins...   A bit like childbirth (bear with me) in that the actual sensation of PAIN is fogged over by the passage of time (not to mention the joys of parenthood) reducing it to something remembered rather than actually FELT. This is why women have second babies.

But I am in the Steve Redgrave phase!  If you see me so much as open my notebooks again, please feel free to shoot me!  In the meanwhile I shall be sleeping, eating, seeing friends, shopping, reading, travelling...LIVING.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>214</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2015-09-14 10:30:02</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2015-09-14 10:30:02</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>closed</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>why-i-write</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="newsletters"><![CDATA[Newsletters]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[3]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_jd_twitter</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_jd_tweet_this</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[yes]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_jd_url</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=214]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_jd_target</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=214]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_jd_wp_twitter</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:1:{i:0;s:99:"I've just put a new post on my blog:  Why I Write http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=214 #fb";}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wpt_status_message</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Tweet sent successfully.]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
				<title>The New Year</title>
		<link>http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=222</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2016 13:08:14 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Amanda]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=222</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA["Time" is a man-made construct.  As far back as the Neolithic period apparently, our ancestors were looking at the moon and devising 'calendars' to mark the phases of the periods they were living through.  Sometimes I like to imagine what it would be like if they (and later, the Gregorians) hadn't bothered: No seconds or minutes or hours or days or weeks or months or years.   No regular markers for our physical passage through life. Christmas, Valentines, Easter, Summer, Halloween, Birthdays... there would be nothing but the constant passing of time.  It would be like floating in space - chaotically unstructured, discombobulating.  Every life would be in a permanent state of existential crisis.  Why bother with anything, when there is nothing to aim for, no hills to climb or corners to turn.

A 'New' Year is crucial to this construct. (I know, I know, many of us spend the first day of it nursing hangovers and staring gloomily at the mounting pile of pine needles under the Christmas tree without being able to summon the wherewithal to put the kettle on, let alone anticipate the mountain of months ahead of us). But AFTER that - when January is in mid-flow - a wonderful feeling can kick in...that uplifting sense of being presented with A(nother) Clean Sheet.  The year stretches ahead, as inviting as a fall of fresh snow.  Life, more than at any other time, feels full of possibilities.  The scent of change is in the air.  The resolutions haven't (yet) been broken.  Plans are (yet) to be made.  Hope springs eternally. As it did the year before, and the one before that.

Which is why, though we live in a digital age and I do lots of digital things...er....digitally, I still have a diary.  Two, in fact.  One on my desk and one by my mainline phone downstairs.  They are the old-fashioned kind of diaries, big, with ribbons to mark the day and two pages for each week.  The diaries reinforce for me all the things I love about this time of year.  The thickness of their pages, the whiteness of the paper...just like that fresh fall of snow.  Finger-scrolling across a screen does not begin to offer the same pleasure, the same sense of hope.  And writing new engagements and commitments onto those pristine pages still feels special too; the effort to be neat is still in place - the pencil is sharp, the words level and evenly spaced.

It all goes to pot of course.  The plans, the neat writing, the hopes.  Like life, it will all get jumbled and mangled; crossed out and re-written.  Tea-spills and muddy cat-paws.  The pages will take their usual bashing, as do we all.

But not yet.  Not while the year is still new.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>222</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2016-01-19 13:08:14</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2016-01-19 13:08:14</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>closed</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>the-new-year</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="newsletters"><![CDATA[Newsletters]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[3]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wpt_failed</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:5:{s:6:"author";b:0;s:8:"sentence";s:100:"I've just put a new post on my blog:  The New Year http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=222 #fb";s:5:"error";s:74:"<strong>Code </strong>: Twitter did not return a recognized response code.";s:4:"code";i:0;s:9:"timestamp";i:1453208925;}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_jd_twitter</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_jd_tweet_this</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[yes]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_jd_url</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=222]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_jd_target</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=222]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wpt_status_message</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[<strong>Code </strong>: Twitter did not return a recognized response code.]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
				<title>Ernest Hemingway: Genius has its drawbacks</title>
		<link>http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=224</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2016 13:55:14 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Amanda]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=224</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[What does it take to win the Nobel Prize for Literature for heaven's sake. I mean, to WIN THE NOBEL PRIZE FOR LITERATURE!!!!!! It makes the Man Booker, or the Orange, or the Costa Award - or indeed anything else - look like...peanuts.

To be honest, and with some shame, I must admit that, while being aware that Ernest Hemingway knew a thing or two about the craft of writing and had churned out some cracking novels (several of which I had read), I had actually FORGOTTEN (if I ever knew) that he actually won the Nobel Prize for Literature.  It was in 1954, since you ask.  And the only reason I was 'reminded' of it was because the other day I plucked one of the hundreds of original penguin paperbacks from the packed book shelves lining my late mother's home and found myself staring at this fact, emblazoned in glorious old-fashioned font, on the jacket of his novel 'To Have and Have Not'.

As it turns out, the award was not for any particular book, but, as the President of the Swedish Nobel Academy put it:

"<em>For his mastery of the art of modern narration.  Hemingway is one of the great authors of our time, one of those who honestly and undauntedly, reproduces the genuine features of the hard countenance of the age.</em>"

So far so good. What a great reason to win the Nobel Prize. Yay!

But Hemingway was also a depressive drunk who just seven years later, at the age of 62, put a bullet through his own brain.

And that got me thinking.  Geniuses often suffer, it is true.  But Hemingway had such heightened powers of wisdom and self -awareness that it seems all the more shocking that he should simply give up on the business of being alive.  To win the greatest prize for literature in the world should have been the pinnacle of his career, shouldn't it?  Something to rejoice, in.  Something to cherish....

At which point it occurred to me (the audacity of implied self-comparison with  a literary giant notwithstanding) that NOTHING would be more potentially damaging to my own, notoriously fragile creative muse than waking up to the fact, every day, of having won the bloomin Nobel Prize for Literature! Where can one possibly go from such an achievement, other than down?  How could one ever write another word that felt good enough? Just the sound of the critics sharpening their knives, ready to lay into whatever was produced next, would  be sufficient to send me scurrying into a dark cave, or reaching for the bottle.  Typically, Hemingway knew this.  Already an alcoholic, and suffering from additional poor health, he famously did not attend the award ceremony, declaring:

"<em>Writing at its best, is a lonely life. Organizations for writers palliate the writer's loneliness but I doubt if they improve his writing. He grows in public stature as he sheds his loneliness and often his work deteriorates. For he does his work alone and if he is a good enough writer he must face eternity, or the lack of it, each day.</em>"

Oh my word, the sadness.  The prescience.  The genius.

I can thoroughly recommend 'To Have and Have Not'.  It offers all that you would hope to find in a Hemingway novel.  It also contains a harrowing paragraph praising the handiness of guns for the purposes of self-annihilation:

<em>Those admirable American instruments so easily carried, so sure of effect, so well designed to end the American dream when it becomes a nightmare, their only drawback the mess they leave for relatives to clean up.</em>

That was written 24 years before he shot himself.  His fourth wife had the pleasure of doing the cleaning up.

I think I'm saying I'm glad I'm not a genius.  I think I'm saying I'm glad I'm never going to win a Nobel Prize.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>224</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2016-03-26 13:55:14</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2016-03-26 13:55:14</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>closed</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>ernest-hemingway-genius-has-its-drawbacks</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="newsletters"><![CDATA[Newsletters]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[3]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_jd_twitter</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_jd_tweet_this</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[yes]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_jd_url</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=224]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_jd_target</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=224]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_jd_wp_twitter</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:1:{i:0;s:130:"I've just put a new post on my blog:  Ernest Hemingway: Genius has its drawbacks http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=224 #fb";}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wpt_status_message</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Tweet sent successfully.]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
				<title>Human Endeavour</title>
		<link>http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=228</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2016 11:38:34 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Amanda]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=228</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[So.  We are in the thick of the Olympics, and no, I didn't think I would get sucked in, because how could I ever care as much as I did four years ago, and besides, I am having a busy summer - places to go, people to see, stuff to write..........

But somehow the sucking in has happened anyway.  Reader, I have been glued to:

The riders with the double-barreled names who were too slow or knocked down too many fences.

Those women rowers who weren't supposed to get anywhere because one of them had come out of retirement aged 40 (!!!)

That skinny lad who got bronze flipping into impossible positions in the gymnastics

Those divers, not just Tom Daley, but that pair who got gold who share a house together in Harrogate...or somewhere.....one of whom was in a coma four years ago, not expected to walk again let alone dive.

Not to mention the cyclists, Frome worn to a skeleton, and those three young lads (I never understand the cycling races) who beat the New Zealanders to gold by a slither of a second.........

And on it goes.  And the reason I mention it is because every time - EVERY.TIME - I watch this striving I find myself getting choked up.  I cry.  I cry if they lose and I cry if they win.  And though some might say that is because I am turning into a sentimental old bat, I would refute that accusation and say instead that the older I get the more I am awestruck by the sheer ENDEAVOUR of which humans are capable.  To TRY that hard at something over years and years, with all the manifold possibilities of failure staring you in the face - either through bad luck, or error, or simply not being good enough! - this to me is the essence of everyday heroism and it moves me deeply.

&nbsp;]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>228</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2016-08-12 11:38:34</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2016-08-12 11:38:34</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>closed</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>human-endeavour</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="newsletters"><![CDATA[Newsletters]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[3]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_jd_twitter</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_jd_tweet_this</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[yes]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_jd_url</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=228]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_jd_target</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=228]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_jd_wp_twitter</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:1:{i:0;s:103:"I've just put a new post on my blog:  Human Endeavour http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=228 #fb";}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wpt_status_message</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Tweet sent successfully.]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
				<title>Getting A Dog</title>
		<link>http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=230</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2016 11:57:24 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Amanda]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=230</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[Once upon a time, a million years ago, in answer to the question 'What do you want to be when you grow up', I would always reply - without hesitation, and certainly no trace of irony - "a kennel maid".  As a child I could conjure no better employment prospect than working with animals as wonderful as my grandparents' lab, Kim.  Not even getting bitten on the nose by Kim put me off.  The poor dog had his mouth in his dinner bowl at the time and I had decided it would be fun to pretend to eat his food with him - on hands and knees, growling, as one does, aged 8. Kim snapped and drew blood.  I cried but got little sympathy.  Dinner time was the highlight of Kim's day, explained the adults dabbing at my nose, all 10 seconds of it, and Kim should allowed to relish those seconds in peace. It all made perfect sense to me.

By my teenage years my career ambitions had broadened somewhat (not much!), while my passion for dogs found partial satisfaction thanks to my parents at last getting a family hound: Moojik, a dear and un-trainable Tibetan terrier who ruled the roost and stole all our hearts until his dying day thirteen years later.

I think it was having children that finally saw off the last of the kennel-maid urges.  The Commitment.  The Responsibility.  The Hard Work.  Not Just For Christmas etc.  And that was just the kids.  They begged for a puppy, as children do, but I held firm and got two cats instead, one for each son.  Both animals lived to a ripe age and could not have been more loved or loving.  Job done.

Then I found myself divorced and my youngest re-started his Get A Dog campaign.  One day I found this propped on my desk:<b><i>    </i></b>

<b><i>AGAINST: Time, Flexibility probs, Long term, Need to reinforce garden</i></b>

<b><i>FOR: Happy for 12 years, Healthy (prolong life), May make dog friends, New idea for book/blogs, Puppy tweets, Facebook pictures, May eat Tiger Lily</i></b> <em>(problem rescue-cat, now a sweetheart)</em><strong>, Companion in empty house, Incentive for people to visit, You may actually love it, New Chapter in life, If not now it won't be before you are 60 - poor dog!</strong><b><i>                                                                                           </i></b>

I quote the list to show a. What a battle that child fought  and b. What a clever, prescient chap he was/is!

But still I resisted, because, while the arguments were powerful - and TRUE - I did not yet feel ready in my own heart to take the leap.  I wanted to get a dog when...........I really WANTED TO GET A DOG.  The point being that, as with having children, the only way of enjoying the commitment is to decide to buy into it 100%.  No resentment.  No regret.  Nothing but throwing oneself at the duties and the pleasures that go hand-in-hand.

And so here we are.  Five years on and I have, for 3 weeks now, been the proud owner of Mabel, a golden retriever poodle cross.  She is very fluffy.  Indeed, the dog-keen son worries that she is 99% poodle and 1% retriever.  Time will tell.  But she has gangly legs, and a bit of a John Wayne swagger when she walks, and big floppy apricot ears, so I think lots of the golden retriever will push through.  Not that I give a damn.  I have fallen, you see, the proverbial hook, line and sinker, exactly as I hoped I would.  She is Mabel.  She needs attention, and clearing up after, and taking out in the mud and the rain, and playing with, and feeding, and training, and health check-ups, and watching like a hawk because her preferred choice of snack is pebbles and/or dead slugs/snails who may/may not have met their maker thanks to lethal slug pellets.

Looking at that 'Against' points now, I would move 'long term' to the other side.  I want Mabel to be long term, you see, as long term as possible.  What's more, the garden has indeed been 'reinforced' which means Mabel can not only call it a play-pen but the zillions of foxes fouling it for the last ten years have disappeared.  That leaves the 'time' and 'flexibility' drawbacks, but set against the benefits of sheer joy, and entertainment, and health (mental as well as physical), they pale into insignificance.

And so far Tiger Lily remains uneaten.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>230</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2016-09-29 11:57:24</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2016-09-29 11:57:24</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>closed</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>getting-a-dog</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="newsletters"><![CDATA[Newsletters]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[3]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_jd_twitter</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_jd_tweet_this</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[yes]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_jd_url</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=230]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_jd_target</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=230]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_jd_wp_twitter</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:1:{i:0;s:101:"I've just put a new post on my blog:  Getting A Dog http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=230 #fb";}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wpt_status_message</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Tweet sent successfully.]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
				<title>My Sixteenth Novel</title>
		<link>http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=243</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2017 11:47:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Amanda]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=243</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[I had hoped that by now, Spring 2017, I would be posting a blog about the launch of my latest novel, 'Good Girls'.  It has been finished for many months.  Indeed, I am already well into that enjoyable early phase of my next work-in-progress, when everything still feels possible as opposed to flailing out of control and needing pinning down.

The dispiriting truth about 'Good Girls' however, is that it has yet to find a publisher.  With fifteen titles under my belt - averaging a novel every two years over a thirty year career - not to mention many hundreds of thousands of sales, this has come as a shock.  'Good Girls' is a fine book.  I chose not to sign a contract to write it because I wanted more time than a contract would have allowed in order to make it as good as it could be.  It is far better, I must reluctantly admit, than several books I have had published in the past.  My agent (Agent of The Year, no less, and widely respected) loves it.  Between us we have been working hard to find a willing home. But so far to no avail.

My agent, digging for consolation, has pointed out that I am fortunate not to have suffered rejection before.  And yes, I suppose that's one way of looking at it.  Er...of course I HAVE suffered rejection in my life - some of it truly terrible - but never in terms of getting novels published.  Every book I have written has been greeted by an editor with open arms.

So this hurts.  I mean it REALLY hurts.  In fact, it is something of a body-blow to my intrinsically fragile artistic confidence.  On top of which, I feel bad to be letting down all the readers who DO like my stuff - many of whom have written to me in bafflement asking why there is still no new Amanda Brookfield on the shelves four years after the publication of 'The Love Child'.

Self-publishing of course remains an option.  But after 30 years of mainstream publishing houses - Weidenfeld &amp; Nicholson, Hodder &amp; Stoughton, Penguin - with all the attendant marketing support, branding assistance and publicity strategy that such places provide - I am not yet ready to go down what will be a much narrower, personally highly arduous road in an already extremely overcrowded arena, when all I really want to do is focus my energies on writing my next novel.

Whenever something goes wrong in my life my instinct is always to try to understand why.  Understanding may not provide solutions, but it can offer a certain solace.  So here are my thoughts on why no one has yet stepped forward to publish my sixteenth novel:

1. When reading a work to which they hold no contractual obligation, bombarded editors at publishing houses are predisposed to look for reasons NOT to take a manuscript rather than the other way round.  (This is why a lot of poor books make it onto the shelves).

2. 'Good Girls' will not be a Global Bestseller and make them squillions.  (No, it won't).

3.  Each publisher probably thinks that because 'Good Girls' is a strong, well-written story, "somewhere else" is bound to accept it for publication.  (No, by definition, that is not the case)

4. My clutch of extremely - maddeningly - complimentary rejection letters tells me that Literary Houses judge 'Good Girls' to be too "commercial", while Commercial Houses think it too "literary." i.e. It is a novel that does not fit neatly into an easy marketing 'box'.

4. The story in 'Good Girls' unfurls gradually, taking the reader to some unforseeable, very dark, as well as richly rewarding places.  In other words it is a novel - like all my novels - that requires a certain immersion and commitment for its power to be felt.  But we live in a world that is increasingly about the Quick-Hit: Quick fame, Quick money, Quick thrills, Quick Entertainment.

All of the above notwithstanding, and despite my battered confidence, I remain certain that the many thousands of readers who have enjoyed my previous 15 books will like 'Good Girls'.  Some may even love it.  But because I am not (yet) a global bestseller they remain a minority; and the harsh truth is that as our world sweeps on in its noisy, mighty, unstoppable way, it is always the minorities - the smaller quieter voices - who are the first to be drowned out.

There.  I have fixed my glare upon my problem and I am comforted.

&nbsp;]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>243</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2017-04-26 11:47:27</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2017-04-26 11:47:27</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>closed</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>the-quick-hit-generation</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="newsletters"><![CDATA[Newsletters]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[3]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_jd_twitter</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_jd_tweet_this</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[yes]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_jd_url</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=243]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_jd_target</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=243]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_jd_wp_twitter</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:1:{i:0;s:112:"I've just put a new post on my blog:  The Quick-Hit Generation http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=243 #fb";}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wpt_status_message</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Tweet sent successfully.]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
				<title>Memoirs vs Fiction</title>
		<link>http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=257</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2018 14:20:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Amanda]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=257</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[I never thought I would be one of those novelists who wrote a memoir.  Here are some of the reasons why:

* Making up stuff is much more freeing and fun

* Fiction is satisfyingly infused with the private experience of an author, but without the tie of being dictated or dominated by it

* Fiction allows an author to keep her inner life private and safe

* Who would be interested anyway?

But then my mother went and died and the man I loved walked away and the seams of my life came undone and fiction stopped hitting the spot.  I mean, I didn't even want to read stories let alone write them.  This is what can happen when the reality of one's own narrative becomes too overwhelming - it crushes the ability to be interested in anything else, trapping you in the process.  I stopped seeing the point of my existence.  Suddenly it was as if all that I had believed in, all the foundations I had relied on for stability, had been blasted out of being.  I got buried.  Digging myself out was like having to start over, shovel-load by shovel-load, deciding, on my own, what still mattered in life and what didn't.  Getting my dog, Mabel, was part of that effort.  At the time, I wrote a jolly blog post about it, deliberately giving no indication of the true turmoil going on behind the decision.  I couldn't have borne the self-exposure.  I was too raw, too thin-skinned.  I had one sole focus, and that was how to rebuild my confidence and sense of purpose, day by day, brick by brick; until I had a new wall to hide behind.

It was a friend in the publishing world who first suggested I write about what I was going through.  In fact, being a clever cookie, she suggested I write about getting Mabel - not just a blog post, but a proper book.  What she knew, and I hadn't quite grasped, was that you cannot write about a dog without writing about the dog's owner.  And so my latest book, a memoir and first work of non-fiction, was born:

<strong>For the Love of a Dog: a memoir of meltdown, recovery, and a golden doodle</strong>

In the process, this is what I discovered:

* Not having to make up stuff is freeing and fun

* A memoir is more deeply infused with private experience, but it also demands the disciplines of the novelist for its structure and effect

* My inner life remains as safe as I need it to be

* Many people are interested in dogs, as well as generously empathetic towards the meltdowns of their owners

&nbsp;]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>257</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2018-04-05 14:20:17</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2018-04-05 14:20:17</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>closed</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>memoirs-vs-fiction</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="newsletters"><![CDATA[Newsletters]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[3]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_jd_twitter</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_jd_tweet_this</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[yes]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_jd_url</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=257]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_jd_target</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=257]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_jd_wp_twitter</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:1:{i:0;s:106:"I've just put a new post on my blog:  Memoirs vs Fiction http://www.amandabrookfield.co.uk/blog/?p=257 #fb";}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wpt_status_message</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Tweet sent successfully.]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
</channel>
</rss>
